<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Elasticsearch on breml's blog</title><link>https://breml.github.io/categories/elasticsearch/</link><description>Recent content in Elasticsearch on breml's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://breml.github.io/categories/elasticsearch/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Comment Elasticsearch Mapping</title><link>https://breml.github.io/blog/2016/09/12/comment-elasticsearch-mapping/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://breml.github.io/blog/2016/09/12/comment-elasticsearch-mapping/</guid><description>If you have worked with large Elasticsearch mappings you may also have encountered the problem, that there is no possibility to comment your mapping or indexing template. Unfortunately the Elasticsearch mappings as well as the indexing templates are defined in JSON, which does not allow to add comments.
I thought the same, until I stumbled over Elasticsearch issue 1394 and the linked commit from January 2013, where a single line was added to the the configuration of the JSON factory:</description></item><item><title>Tagging of dynamically added Fields in Elasticsearch</title><link>https://breml.github.io/blog/2015/10/28/tagging-of-dynamically-added-fields-in-elasticsearch/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://breml.github.io/blog/2015/10/28/tagging-of-dynamically-added-fields-in-elasticsearch/</guid><description>At work we use the ELK Stack (Elasticsearch, Logstash and Kibana) to process, store and visualize all kind of log data. To get the most out of the information stored in Elasticsearch, we maintain a handcrafted Elasticsearch mapping.
As we are in the process of continuously adding more and more log sources, now and then our Elasticsearch mapping is not complete. In this case the dynamic mapping feature of Elasticsearch adds these new fields by it&amp;rsquo;s own.</description></item></channel></rss>