<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on breml's blog</title><link>https://breml.github.io/post/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on breml's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://breml.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Detect Trojan Source Attack</title><link>https://breml.github.io/blog/2021/12/07/detect-trojan-source-attack/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://breml.github.io/blog/2021/12/07/detect-trojan-source-attack/</guid><description>What is the Trojan Source Attack The Trojan Source attack became famous on November 1st 2021 by the paper Trojan Source: Invisible Vulnerabilities published by Nicolas Boucher and Ross Anderson and the then following coverage in the security and IT news sites (e.g. 1, 2, 3, 4, 5). The vulnerability is also listed as CVE-2021-42574.
The core of the attack is to use Unicode control characters to reorder tokens in source code.</description></item><item><title>Embed CA Root Certificates in Go Programs</title><link>https://breml.github.io/blog/2021/01/17/embed-ca-root-certificates-in-go-programs/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://breml.github.io/blog/2021/01/17/embed-ca-root-certificates-in-go-programs/</guid><description>Abstract Package rootcerts provides an embedded copy of the Mozilla Included CA Certificate List, more specifically the PEM of Root Certificates in Mozilla&amp;amp;rsquo;s Root Store with the Websites (TLS/SSL) Trust Bit Enabled. If this package is imported anywhere in the program and the crypto/x509 package cannot find the system certificate pool, it will use the embedded certificates instead.
Background In my professional work as well as in my private projects I often deploy Go programs as containers.</description></item><item><title>Comment Elasticsearch Mapping</title><link>https://breml.github.io/blog/2016/09/12/comment-elasticsearch-mapping/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://breml.github.io/blog/2016/09/12/comment-elasticsearch-mapping/</guid><description>If you have worked with large Elasticsearch mappings you may also have encountered the problem, that there is no possibility to comment your mapping or indexing template. Unfortunately the Elasticsearch mappings as well as the indexing templates are defined in JSON, which does not allow to add comments.
I thought the same, until I stumbled over Elasticsearch issue 1394 and the linked commit from January 2013, where a single line was added to the the configuration of the JSON factory:</description></item><item><title>Using MongoDB Backend Service with Go App in the Swisscom App Cloud</title><link>https://breml.github.io/blog/2015/12/22/using-mongodb-backend-service-with-go-app-in-the-swisscom-app-cloud/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://breml.github.io/blog/2015/12/22/using-mongodb-backend-service-with-go-app-in-the-swisscom-app-cloud/</guid><description>Introduction In my last post I described how to create and deploy an app, written with the Google Go language, to the Swisscom Application Cloud. This post is a follow up, in which I would like to share some of the learnings, I discovered while extending the Hello World app, following the ideas for the node.js example.
This blog post is not a detailed step by step tutorial, but rather points out the in my opinion important steps to understand how to get a Go app running in the App Cloud with a MongoDB backend.</description></item><item><title>Deploy a Go Web App to the Swisscom Application Cloud</title><link>https://breml.github.io/blog/2015/12/17/deploy-a-go-web-app-to-the-swisscom-application-cloud/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://breml.github.io/blog/2015/12/17/deploy-a-go-web-app-to-the-swisscom-application-cloud/</guid><description>Inspired by the this blog post about the deployment of a node.js example app to the Swisscom Application Cloud, I decided to test the Swisscom Application Cloud my self with a similar app, written in Google Go language.
This blog should take you through the essential steps on a Linux based system to push your own Go based app to a Cloud Foundry based app cloud, for example the one from Swisscom.</description></item><item><title>Tagging of dynamically added Fields in Elasticsearch</title><link>https://breml.github.io/blog/2015/10/28/tagging-of-dynamically-added-fields-in-elasticsearch/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://breml.github.io/blog/2015/10/28/tagging-of-dynamically-added-fields-in-elasticsearch/</guid><description>At work we use the ELK Stack (Elasticsearch, Logstash and Kibana) to process, store and visualize all kind of log data. To get the most out of the information stored in Elasticsearch, we maintain a handcrafted Elasticsearch mapping.
As we are in the process of continuously adding more and more log sources, now and then our Elasticsearch mapping is not complete. In this case the dynamic mapping feature of Elasticsearch adds these new fields by it&amp;rsquo;s own.</description></item><item><title>Dividable without remainder</title><link>https://breml.github.io/blog/2015/10/22/dividable-without-remainder/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://breml.github.io/blog/2015/10/22/dividable-without-remainder/</guid><description>Summary Problem For a &amp;ldquo;1 in n sampling&amp;rdquo; problem I was looking for a fast way to determine, if a value x (random number) is dividable by a previously known divisor d (sampling rate) without remainder. So the algorithm has to result with true in 1 of d cases, otherwise with false. x and d are both unsigned integers, in my case 32 bit long. Since the algorithm will be used for sampling and x is produced by a random number generator (see below: Motivation), a slight inaccuracy (&amp;lt; 0.</description></item><item><title>gogitignore</title><link>https://breml.github.io/blog/2015/10/06/gogitignore/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://breml.github.io/blog/2015/10/06/gogitignore/</guid><description>The other day I extended one of my go (golang) project with some new main packages resulting in new commands. After building the project with go build the resulting executables are placed in the respective directories within the project. While updating the git repository I found it cumbersome to add all the new executables to the .gitignore-file. On linux there is unfortunately now easy way to exclude all executables within a project with a single line in .</description></item></channel></rss>